<TitlePage>
  <Title>Functionally recursive groups</Title>
  <Subtitle>Self-similar groups</Subtitle>
  <Version>Version &Version;</Version>
  <TitleComment>
    Groups generated by automata or satisfying functional recursions
  </TitleComment>
  <Author>Laurent Bartholdi
	  <Email><Alt Only="HTML">laurent dot bartholdi at gmail dot com</Alt>
		 <Alt Not="HTML">laurent.bartholdi@gmail.com</Alt></Email>
	  <Homepage>https://www.math.uni-sb.de/ag/bartholdi/</Homepage>
  </Author>
  <Date>&Date;</Date>
  <Address>
  Mathematisches Institut<Br/>Bunsenstraße 3-5<Br/>D-37073 Göttingen<Br/>Germany
  </Address>
  <Abstract>
    This document describes the package <Package>FR</Package>, which
    implements in &GAP; the basic objects of Mealy machines and
    functional recursions; and handles groups that they generate.
  <Alt Only="HTML">
  <P/>
  The computer algebra system &GAP; is available at
  <URL>https://www.gap-system.org</URL>.
  <P/>
  This documentation for <Package>FR</Package> is available at
  <URL>https://www.gap-system.org/Manuals/pkg/fr-&Version;/doc/manual.pdf</URL> in PDF
  format, and may be accessed online at
  <URL>https://gap-packages.github.io/fr/</URL>.
  <P/>
  The latest release of the package may be downloaded as
  <URL>https://github.com/gap-packages/fr/archive/&Version;.tar.gz</URL> (tar, gzipped) and <URL>https://github.com/gap-packages/fr/archive/&Version;.zip</URL> (zip). The latest repository version (possibly unstable) may be downloaded as <URL>https://github.com/gap-packages/fr/tarball/master</URL> (tar, gzipped),
  <URL>https://github.com/gap-packages/fr.git</URL> (git repository), or
  explored at <URL>https://github.com/gap-packages/fr/tree/master/</URL>.
  </Alt>
  <P/>
    Groups defined by a recursive action on a rooted tree can
    be defined in &GAP; via their recursion. Various algorithms are
    implemented to manipulate these groups and their elements.
  <P/>
    For comments or questions on <Package>FR</Package> please contact
    the author; this package is still under development.
  </Abstract>
  <Copyright>&copyright; 2006-2012 by Laurent Bartholdi
  </Copyright>
  <Acknowledgements>Part of this work is/was supported by the
  "Swiss National Fund for Scientific Research" and the
  "German Science Foundation".
  </Acknowledgements>
  <Colophon>
  This project started in the mid-1990s, when, as a PhD student I did
  many calculations with groups generated by automata, and realized
  the similarities between all calculations; it quickly became clear
  that these calculations could be done much better by a computer than
  by a human.

  <P/> The first routines I wrote constructed finite representations
  of the groups considered, so as to get insight from fast
  calculations within &GAP;. The results then had to be proved correct
  within the infinite group under consideration, and this often
  involved guessing appropriate words in the infinite group with a
  given image in the finite quotient.

  <P/> Around 2000, I had developed quite a few routines, which I
  assembled in a &GAP; package, that dealt directly with infinite
  groups. This package was primitive at its core, but was extended
  with various routines as they became useful.

  <P/> I decided in late 2005 to start a new package from scratch,
  that would encorporate as much functionality as possible in a
  uniform manner; that would handle semigroups as well as groups; that
  could be easily extended; and with a complete, understandable
  documentation. I hope I am not too far from these objectives.
  </Colophon>

</TitlePage>
